<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.indentation.IndentationCheck"
             name="Indentation"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.TreeWalker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Checks correct indentation of Java code.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 The idea behind this is that while
 pretty printers are sometimes convenient for bulk reformats of
 legacy code, they often either aren't configurable enough or
 just can't anticipate how format should be done. Sometimes this is
 personal preference, other times it is practical experience. In any
 case, this check should just ensure that a minimal set of indentation
 rules is followed.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Basic offset indentation is used for indentation inside code blocks.
 For any lines that span more than 1, line wrapping indentation is used for those lines
 after the first. Brace adjustment, case, and throws indentations are all used only if
 those specific identifiers start the line. If, for example, a brace is used in the
 middle of the line, its indentation will not take effect. All indentations have an
 accumulative/recursive effect when they are triggered. If during a line wrapping, another
 code block is found and it doesn't end on that same line, then the subsequent lines
 afterwards, in that new code block, are increased on top of the line wrap and any
 indentations above it.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Example:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;pre&gt;
 if ((condition1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; condition2)
         || (condition3 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; condition4)    // line wrap with bigger indentation
         ||!(condition5 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; condition6)) { // line wrap with bigger indentation
   field.doSomething()                    // basic offset
       .doSomething()                     // line wrap
       .doSomething( c -&amp;gt; {               // line wrap
         return c.doSome();               // basic offset
       });
 }
 &lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <properties>
        <property default-value="4" name="arrayInitIndent" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far an array initialization
 should be indented when on next line.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="4" name="basicOffset" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far new indentation level should be
 indented when on the next line.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="0" name="braceAdjustment" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far a braces should be indented
 when on the next line.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="4" name="caseIndent" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far a case label should be indented
 when on next line.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="false" name="forceStrictCondition" type="boolean">
          <description>Force strict indent level in line
 wrapping case. If value is true, line wrap indent have to be same as
 lineWrappingIndentation parameter. If value is false, line wrap indent
 could be bigger on any value user would like.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="4" name="lineWrappingIndentation" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far continuation line
 should be indented when line-wrapping is present.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="4" name="throwsIndent" type="int">
          <description>Specify how far a throws clause should be
 indented when on next line.</description>
        </property>
      </properties>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="indentation.child.error"/>
        <message-key key="indentation.child.error.multi"/>
        <message-key key="indentation.error"/>
        <message-key key="indentation.error.multi"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
