<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.NewlineAtEndOfFileCheck"
             name="NewlineAtEndOfFile"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.Checker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Checks whether files end with a line separator.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Rationale: Any source files and text files in general should end with a line
 separator to let other easily add new content at the end of file and "diff"
 command does not show previous lines as changed.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Example (the line with 'No newline at end of file' should not be in the diff):
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;pre&gt;
 &amp;#64;&amp;#64; -32,4 +32,5 &amp;#64;&amp;#64; ForbidWildcardAsReturnTypeCheck.returnTypeClassNamesIgnoreRegex
 PublicReferenceToPrivateTypeCheck.name = Public Reference To Private Type

 StaticMethodCandidateCheck.name = Static Method Candidate
 -StaticMethodCandidateCheck.desc = Checks whether private methods should be declared as static.
 \ No newline at end of file
 +StaticMethodCandidateCheck.desc = Checks whether private methods should be declared as static.
 +StaticMethodCandidateCheck.skippedMethods = Method names to skip during the check.
 &lt;/pre&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 It can also trick the VCS to report the wrong owner for such lines.
 An engineer who has added nothing but a newline character becomes the last
 known author for the entire line. As a result, a mate can ask him a question
 to which he will not give the correct answer.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Old Rationale: CVS source control management systems will even print
 a warning when it encounters a file that doesn't end with a line separator.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Attention: property fileExtensions works with files that are passed by similar
 property for at &lt;a href="https://checkstyle.org/config.html#Checker"&gt;Checker&lt;/a&gt;.
 Please make sure required file extensions are mentioned at Checker's fileExtensions property.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 This will check against the platform-specific default line separator.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 It is also possible to enforce the use of a specific line-separator across
 platforms, with the {@code lineSeparator} property.
 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <properties>
        <property default-value="" name="fileExtensions" type="java.lang.String[]">
          <description>Specify the file extensions of the files to process.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="lf_cr_crlf"
                      name="lineSeparator"
                      type="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.LineSeparatorOption">
          <description>Specify the type of line separator.</description>
        </property>
      </properties>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="noNewlineAtEOF"/>
        <message-key key="unable.open"/>
        <message-key key="wrong.line.end"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
