<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.TrailingCommentCheck"
             name="TrailingComment"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.TreeWalker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 The check to ensure that lines with code do not end with comment.
 For the case of {@code //} comments that means that the only thing that should precede
 it is whitespace. It doesn't check comments if they do not end a line; for example,
 it accepts the following: &lt;code&gt;Thread.sleep( 10 /*some comment here&amp;#42;/ );&lt;/code&gt;
 Format property is intended to deal with the &lt;code&gt;} // while&lt;/code&gt; example.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Rationale: Steve McConnell in &lt;cite&gt;Code Complete&lt;/cite&gt; suggests that endline
 comments are a bad practice. An end line comment would be one that is on
 the same line as actual code. For example:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;pre&gt;
 a = b + c;      // Some insightful comment
 d = e / f;        // Another comment for this line
 &lt;/pre&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Quoting &lt;cite&gt;Code Complete&lt;/cite&gt; for the justification:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 "The comments have to be aligned so that they do not interfere with the visual
 structure of the code. If you don't align them neatly, they'll make your listing
 look like it's been through a washing machine."
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 "Endline comments tend to be hard to format...It takes time to align them.
 Such time is not spent learning more about the code; it's dedicated solely
 to the tedious task of pressing the spacebar or tab key."
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 "Endline comments are also hard to maintain. If the code on any line containing
 an endline comment grows, it bumps the comment farther out, and all the other
 endline comments will have to bumped out to match. Styles that are hard to
 maintain aren't maintained...."
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 "Endline comments also tend to be cryptic. The right side of the line doesn't
 offer much room and the desire to keep the comment on one line means the comment
 must be short. Work then goes into making the line as short as possible instead
 of as clear as possible. The comment usually ends up as cryptic as possible...."
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 "A systemic problem with endline comments is that it's hard to write a meaningful
 comment for one line of code. Most endline comments just repeat the line of code,
 which hurts more than it helps."
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 McConnell's comments on being hard to maintain when the size of the line changes
 are even more important in the age of automated refactorings.
 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <properties>
        <property default-value="" name="format" type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify pattern for strings allowed before the comment.</description>
        </property>
        <property name="legalComment" type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Define pattern for text allowed in trailing comments.
 This pattern will not be applied to multiline comments.</description>
        </property>
      </properties>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="trailing.comments"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
