<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
   <module>
      <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.TranslationCheck"
             name="Translation"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.Checker">
         <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Ensures the correct translation of code by checking property files for consistency
 regarding their keys. Two property files describing one and the same context
 are consistent if they contain the same keys. TranslationCheck also can check
 an existence of required translations which must exist in project, if
 {@code requiredTranslations} option is used.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Language code for the property {@code requiredTranslations} is composed of
 the lowercase, two-letter codes as defined by
 &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_ISO_639-1_codes"&gt;ISO 639-1&lt;/a&gt;.
 Default value is empty String Set which means that only the existence of default
 translation is checked. Note, if you specify language codes (or just one
 language code) of required translations the check will also check for existence
 of default translation files in project.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Note: If your project uses preprocessed translation files and the original files do not have the
 {@code properties} extension, you can specify additional file extensions
 via the {@code fileExtensions} property.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Attention: the check will perform the validation of ISO codes if the option
 is used. So, if you specify, for example, "mm" for language code,
 TranslationCheck will rise violation that the language code is incorrect.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Attention: this Check could produce false-positives if it is used with
 &lt;a href="https://checkstyle.org/config.html#Checker"&gt;Checker&lt;/a&gt; that use cache
 (property "cacheFile") This is known design problem, will be addressed at
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/checkstyle/checkstyle/issues/3539"&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
         <properties>
            <property default-value="^messages.*$"
                      name="baseName"
                      type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
               <description>Specify
 &lt;a href="https://docs.oracle.com/en/java/javase/11/docs/api/java.base/java/util/ResourceBundle.html"&gt;
 Base name&lt;/a&gt; of resource bundles which contain message resources.
 It helps the check to distinguish config and localization resources.</description>
            </property>
            <property default-value=".properties"
                      name="fileExtensions"
                      type="java.lang.String[]">
               <description>Specify the file extensions of the files to process.</description>
            </property>
            <property default-value=""
                      name="requiredTranslations"
                      type="java.lang.String[]">
               <description>Specify language codes of required
 translations which must exist in project.</description>
            </property>
         </properties>
         <message-keys>
            <message-key key="translation.missingKey"/>
            <message-key key="translation.missingTranslationFile"/>
         </message-keys>
      </check>
   </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
