<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <filter fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.filters.SuppressWithPlainTextCommentFilter"
              name="SuppressWithPlainTextCommentFilter"
              parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.Checker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Filter {@code SuppressWithPlainTextCommentFilter} uses plain text to suppress
 audit events. The filter can be used only to suppress audit events received
 from the checks which implement FileSetCheck interface. In other words, the
 checks which have Checker as a parent module. The filter knows nothing about
 AST, it treats only plain text comments and extracts the information required
 for suppression from the plain text comments. Currently, the filter supports
 only single-line comments.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Please, be aware of the fact that, it is not recommended to use the filter
 for Java code anymore, however you still are able to use it to suppress audit
 events received from the checks which implement FileSetCheck interface.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Rationale: Sometimes there are legitimate reasons for violating a check.
 When this is a matter of the code in question and not personal preference,
 the best place to override the policy is in the code itself. Semi-structured
 comments can be associated with the check. This is sometimes superior to
 a separate suppressions file, which must be kept up-to-date as the source
 file is edited.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Note that the suppression comment should be put before the violation.
 You can use more than one suppression comment each on separate line.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Properties {@code offCommentFormat} and {@code onCommentFormat} must have equal
 &lt;a href="https://docs.oracle.com/en/java/javase/11/docs/api/java.base/java/util/regex/Matcher.html#groupCount()"&gt;
 paren counts&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 SuppressionWithPlainTextCommentFilter can suppress Checks that have Treewalker or
 Checker as parent module.
 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <properties>
        <property default-value=".*"
                      name="checkFormat"
                      type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify check pattern to suppress.</description>
        </property>
        <property name="idFormat" type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify check ID pattern to suppress.</description>
        </property>
        <property name="messageFormat" type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify message pattern to suppress.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="// CHECKSTYLE:OFF"
                      name="offCommentFormat"
                      type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify comment pattern to trigger filter
 to begin suppression.</description>
        </property>
        <property default-value="// CHECKSTYLE:ON"
                      name="onCommentFormat"
                      type="java.util.regex.Pattern">
          <description>Specify comment pattern to trigger filter
 to end suppression.</description>
        </property>
      </properties>
    </filter>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
