<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 https://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <head>
    <title>Writing Checks</title>
  </head>

  <body>
    <section name="Content">
      <macro name="toc">
        <param name="fromDepth" value="1"/>
        <param name="toDepth" value="1"/>
      </macro>
    </section>

    <section name="Overview">

      <p>
        OK, so you have finally decided to write your own Check.  Welcome
        aboard! This is a really easy thing to do. Very basic Java knowledge is required
        to write a Check. It is good practice even for students.
        There are actually two different types of checks that can be made, each with
        their own requirements. Before you start coding, you will have to find out
        which kind of Check you want to implement.
      </p>

      <p>
        The functionality of Checkstyle is implemented in modules that can
        be plugged into Checkstyle. Modules can be containers for other
        modules, i.e. they form a tree structure. The top level modules
        that are known directly to the Checkstyle kernel (which is also a
        module and forms the root of the tree) implement the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/FileSetCheck.html">FileSetCheck</a>
        interface. These are pretty simple to grasp: they take a set of
        input files and fire violation messages.
      </p>

      <p>
        Checkstyle provides a few FileSetCheck implementations by default.
        One of them is the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/TreeWalker.html">TreeWalker</a>. A
        TreeWalker supports submodules that are derived from the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html">AbstractCheck</a>
        class. The TreeWalker operates by separately transforming each of
        the Java input files into an abstract syntax tree and then handing
        the result over to each of the Check submodules, which in turn have
        a look at a certain aspect of the tree.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Writing Checks">

      <p>
        Most of the functionality of Checkstyle is implemented as
        Checks. If you know how to write your own Checks, you can extend
        Checkstyle according to your needs without having to wait for the
        Checkstyle development team. You are about to become a Checkstyle
        Expert.
      </p>

      <p>
        Suppose you have a convention that the number of methods in a
        class should not exceed 30. This rule makes
        sense. A class should only do one thing and do it well. With a
        zillion methods chances are that the class does more than one
        thing. The only problem you have is that your convention is not
        checked by Checkstyle. You&#39;ll have to write your own Check
        and plug it into the Checkstyle framework.
      </p>

      <p>
        This chapter is organized as a tour that takes you
        through the process of writing a Check step by step and explains both the theoretical
        foundations and the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/package-summary.html">Checkstyle
          API</a> along the way.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Java Grammar">

      <p>
        Every Java Program is structured into files, and each of these
        files has a certain structure. For example, if there is a package statement,
        it is always the first line of a file that is not comment or whitespace.
        After the package statement comes a list of import statements, which
        is followed by a class or interface definition, and so on.
      </p>
      <p>
        If you have ever read an introductory level Java book, you probably
        knew all of the above. And if you have studied computer science,
        you probably also know that the rules that specify the Java language
        can be formally specified using a grammar, though this statement is
        simplified for didactic purposes.
      </p>
      <p>
        There are tools which read a grammar definition and produce a parser
        for the language that is specified in the grammar. In other
        words, the output of the tool is a program that can transform a
        stream of characters (a Java file) into a tree representation
        that reflects the structure of the file (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_syntax_tree">
        an Abstract Syntax Tree or AST</a>).
        Checkstyle uses the parser generator <a href="https://www.antlr.org">ANTLR</a>,
        but that is an implementation detail you do not need to worry about
        when writing Checks, as this well tested parser will parse Java files
        for you.
      </p>

    </section>
    <section name="Printing a Java tree structure">
      <p>
        Checkstyle can print an AST for a java file. To do so, run
        the checkstyle jar file with the <b>-t</b> or <b>-T</b> argument,
        providing the java file.
      </p>
      <p>For example, take this MyClass.java file:</p>
      <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java"><![CDATA[
/**
 * My <b>class</b>.
 * @see AbstractClass
 */
public class MyClass {

}
      ]]></code></pre></div>
      <div class="wrapper">
        <table style="table-layout: fixed;">
          <tr>
            <td>
              1) Using -t as parameter.
              <br />
              java -jar checkstyle-X.XX-all.jar -t MyClass.java
            </td>
            <td>
              2) Using -T as parameter.
              <br />
              java -jar checkstyle-X.XX-all.jar -T MyClass.java
            </td>
          </tr>

          <tr>
            <td>
              <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java"><![CDATA[
CLASS_DEF -> CLASS_DEF [5:0]
|--MODIFIERS -> MODIFIERS [5:0]
|   `--LITERAL_PUBLIC -> public [5:0]
|--LITERAL_CLASS -> class [5:7]
|--IDENT -> MyClass [5:13]
`--OBJBLOCK -> OBJBLOCK [5:21]
    |--LCURLY -> { [5:21]
    `--RCURLY -> } [7:0]
 ]]>
              </code></pre></div>
            </td>
            <td>
              <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java"><![CDATA[
CLASS_DEF -> CLASS_DEF [5:0]
|--MODIFIERS -> MODIFIERS [5:0]
|   |--BLOCK_COMMENT_BEGIN -> /* [1:0]
|   |   |--COMMENT_CONTENT -> *\n * My <b>class</b>.\n * @see AbstractClass\n  [1:2]
|   |   `--BLOCK_COMMENT_END -> */ [4:1]
|   `--LITERAL_PUBLIC -> public [5:0]
|--LITERAL_CLASS -> class [5:7]
|--IDENT -> MyClass [5:13]
`--OBJBLOCK -> OBJBLOCK [5:21]
    |--LCURLY -> { [5:21]
    `--RCURLY -> } [7:0]
]]>
              </code></pre></div>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </div>
      <p>
        As you can see, a very small java file transforms to a huge Abstract Syntax Tree, because
        this creates a very detailed tree that includes all components of the java file:
        object blocks, comments, modifiers, etc.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="The Checkstyle SDK Gui">
      <p>
        Still with us? Great, you have mastered the basic theory so here
        is your reward - a GUI that displays the structure of a Java source file.
        Run the gui with the command:
      </p>
      <div class="wrap-content">
        <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
          java -cp checkstyle-${projectVersion}-all.jar com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.gui.Main
        </code></pre></div>
      </div>

      <p>
        Click the button at the bottom of the frame
        and select a syntactically correct Java source file. The frame
        will be populated with a tree that corresponds to the structure
        of the Java source code.
      </p>

      <p>
        <span class="wrapper block">
          <img alt="screenshot" src="images/gui_screenshot.png"/>
        </span>
      </p>

      <p>
        In the leftmost column you can open and close branches
        of the tree. The remaining columns display information about each node
        in the tree. The second column displays a token type for each node. As
        you navigate from the root of the tree to one of the leafs, you&#39;ll
        notice that the token type denotes smaller and smaller units of your
        source file, i.e. close to the root you might see the token type
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html#CLASS_DEF">CLASS_DEF</a>
        (a node that represents a class definition), while you will see token
        types like IDENT (an identifier) near the leaves of the tree.
      </p>

      <p>
        In the bottom of frame you can find buttons "Open File", "Reload File"
        and a dropdown list with parse modes to choose. In the first option,
        after choosing a file, a tree that corresponds to the java source
        file is shown. Notice that only files with the ".java" extension
        can be opened. The second option reloads the previously opened file from file system and
        rebuilds the tree.
      </p>

      <p>
        In the dropdown list next to "Modes" are three different
        parse modes: "PLAIN JAVA", "JAVA WITH COMMENTS", "JAVA WITH JAVADOC AND COMMENTS".
        "PLAIN JAVA" mode shows the AST corresponding to the java source code without comments. In
        "JAVA WITH COMMENTS" you can also see comments blocks on the tree. Lastly, when
        "JAVA WITH JAVADOC AND COMMENTS" is chosen the javadoc tree builds and attaches
        to every comment block that contains javadoc.
      </p>

      <p>
        Note: The text of a tree node and its children is selected automatically
        after either pressing "Enter" or double-clicking on it. There is no
        need to make a selection manually.
      </p>

      <p>
        We&#39;ll get back to the details in the other columns later. They are important for
        implementing Checks but not for understanding the basic concepts. For now, it is sufficient
        to know that the gui is a tool that lets you look at the structure of a Java file, i.e. you
        can see the Java grammar &#39;in action&#39;.
      </p>

      <p> If you use <a href="https://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</a> you can install the
        <a href="https://github.com/sevntu-checkstyle/checkstyle-ast-eclipse-viewer">
          Checkstyle AST Eclipse Viewer</a>
        plugin to launch that application from context menu on any file in Eclipse.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Understanding the visitor pattern">

      <p>
        Ready for a bit more theory? The last bit
        that is missing before you can start writing Checks is understanding
        the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visitor_pattern">Visitor pattern</a>.
      </p>

      <p>
        When working with an AST, a simple approach to writing Checks
        on them would be to add a <code>check()</code> method to the class that defines
        the AST nodes. For example, our AST type could have a method
        <code>checkNumberOfMethods()</code>. Such an approach would suffer from a few
        serious drawbacks. Most importantly, it does not provide an extensible
        design, i.e. the Checks have to be known at compile time; there is no
        way to write plugins.
      </p>

      <p>
        Hence, Checkstyle&#39;s AST classes do not have any
        methods that implement checking functionality. Instead,
        Checkstyle&#39;s
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/TreeWalker.html">TreeWalker</a>
        takes a set of objects that extend the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html">AbstractCheck</a>
        class. A Check provides methods that take an AST as an argument and
        perform the checking process for that AST, most prominently
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#visitToken(com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.DetailAST)">
          <code>visitToken()</code>
        </a>.
      </p>

      <p>
        It is important to understand that the individual
        Checks do not drive the AST traversal (it is possible
        to traverse the tree manually, but not recommended).
        Instead, the TreeWalker traverses the tree using a
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_traversal">tree traversal (depth-first)</a>
        algorithm, and calls the Check&#39;s methods.
      </p>

      <p>
        Before any visitor method is called, the TreeWalker will call
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#beginTree(com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.DetailAST)">
          <code>beginTree</code>
        </a> to give the Check a chance to do
        some initialization. Then, when performing the traversal from
        the root to the leaf nodes, the <code>visitToken()</code>
        method is called. Unlike the basic examples in the pattern book, there
        is a <code>visitToken()</code> counterpart called
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#leaveToken(com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.DetailAST)">
          <code>leaveToken</code>
        </a>. The TreeWalker will call that
        method to signal that the subtree below the node has been processed and
        the TreeWalker is backtracking from the node. After the root node has
        been left, the TreeWalker will call
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#finishTree(com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.DetailAST)">
          <code>finishTree</code>
        </a>.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Visitor in action">

      <p>
        Let&#39;s get back to our example and start writing code - that&#39;s why
        you came here, right? Remember that we are in the process of
        writing a check that limits the amount of methods in a class.
        Firing up the Checkstyle GUI and looking at a few source
        files, we notice that we are interested in the
        number of tree nodes of type METHOD_DEF. The number of such tokens
        should be counted separately for each CLASS_DEF / INTERFACE_DEF.
      </p>

      <p>
        Hence, we need to register the Check for the token types
        CLASS_DEF and INTERFACE_DEF. The TreeWalker will only call
        visitToken for these token types. Because the requirements of
        our tasks are so simple, there is no need to implement the other
        methods (<code>leaveToken()</code>, <code>finishTree()</code>, etc.)
        available to us from AbstractCheck. Here is our first shot at our
        Check implementation:
      </p>

      <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
package com.mycompany.checks;
import com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.*;

public class MethodLimitCheck extends AbstractCheck
{
  private static final int DEFAULT_MAX = 30;
  private int max = DEFAULT_MAX;

  @Override
  public int[] getDefaultTokens()
  {
    return new int[]{TokenTypes.CLASS_DEF, TokenTypes.INTERFACE_DEF};
  }

  @Override
  public void visitToken(DetailAST ast)
  {
    // find the OBJBLOCK node below the CLASS_DEF/INTERFACE_DEF
    DetailAST objBlock = ast.findFirstToken(TokenTypes.OBJBLOCK);

    // count the number of direct children of the OBJBLOCK
    // that are METHOD_DEFS
    int methodDefs = objBlock.getChildCount(TokenTypes.METHOD_DEF);

    // report violation if limit is reached
    if (methodDefs > this.max) {
      String message = "too many methods, only " + this.max + " are allowed";
      log(ast.getLineNo(), message);
    }
  }
}
      </code></pre></div>

    </section>

    <section name="Understanding token sets">

      <p>
        There are four methods in Check class to control the processed
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html">TokenTypes</a> -
        one setter
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#setTokens-java.lang.String...-">
        setTokens()</a>, which is used to define a custom set (which is different
        from the default one) of the processed TokenTypes via config file and
        three getters, which have to be overridden:
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#getDefaultTokens--">
        getDefaultTokens()</a>,
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#getAcceptableTokens--">
        getAcceptableTokens()</a>,
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#getRequiredTokens--">
        getRequiredTokens()</a>.
      </p>

      <ul>

        <li>
          getDefaultTokens() - returns a set of TokenTypes which are processed in the
          <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#visitToken-com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.DetailAST-">
          visitToken()</a> method by default.
        </li>

        <li>
          getRequiredTokens() - returns a set of TokenTypes which Check must be subscribed to for
          a valid execution. If the user wants to specify a custom set of TokenTypes then
          this set must contain all the TokenTypes from RequiredTokens.
        </li>

        <li>
          getAcceptableTokens() - returns a set, which contains all the TokenTypes that
          can be processed by the check. Both DefaultTokens and RequiredTokens and any custom
          set of TokenTypes are subsets of AcceptableTokens.
        </li>

      </ul>

    </section>

    <section name="Comment Tokens in AST">

      <p>
        Before <a href="releasenotes_old_6-0_7-8.html#Release_6.0">Checkstyle 6.0</a>,
        there were no comments in the AST. Comments are not code and are ignored by compiler,
        so they were not the primary focus of Checkstyle,
        but more and more requests appeared to do validation of javadoc and comments.
        One simple solution was to receive the plain-text of the file in a Check, manually parse
        it for any custom comments and validation.
      </p>
      <p>
        In version 6.0, a method was added to the AbstractCheck class which allows you to see
        comment nodes in the AST -
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractCheck.html#isCommentNodesRequired--">
        isCommentNodesRequired()</a>. When this returns `true`, comments are included
        in the AST alongside the code.
      </p>
      <p>
        This feature is optional to maintain backwards compatibility with existing checks,
        as it changes the AST structure and many existing checks were not ready for this change.
        Checkstyle does not parse the files twice to include the comments.
        Comments were already in the grammar and parsed, but skipped
        during the creation of AST nodes.
      </p>
      <p>
        Before execution, all Checks are divided into 2 groups (based on the isCommentNodesRequired
        method): "PLAIN JAVA" and "JAVA WITH COMMENTS".
        Checkstyle executes "java only Checks" first. When those checks are all finished,
        Checkstyle appends the comment AST nodes to the AST and calls "comment Checks".
        All Javadoc Checks that are a child of
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/checks/javadoc/AbstractJavadocCheck.html">
          <code>AbstractJavadocCheck</code>
        </a>are "comment Checks".
        (See also <a href="writingjavadocchecks.html">'Writing Javadoc Checks'</a>)
      </p>
      <p>
        The following Comment specific tokens exist:
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html#SINGLE_LINE_COMMENT">
            SINGLE_LINE_COMMENT</a>,
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html#BLOCK_COMMENT_BEGIN">
            BLOCK_COMMENT_BEGIN</a>,
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html#BLOCK_COMMENT_END">
            BLOCK_COMMENT_END</a>,
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/TokenTypes.html#COMMENT_CONTENT">
            COMMENT_CONTENT</a>.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Navigating the AST">

      <p>
        In the example above you already saw that the DetailsAST class
        provides utility methods to extract information from the tree,
        like <code>getChildCount()</code>. By now you have
        probably consulted the API documentation - and if not, you should -
        and found that
        <a href="https://github.com/checkstyle/checkstyle/blob/master/src/main/java/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/DetailAST.java">
            DetailsAST</a> additionally provides methods for navigating around
        in the syntax tree, like finding the next sibling of a node, the
        children of a node, the parent of a node, etc.
      </p>

      <p>
        These methods provide great power for developing complex
        Checks. Most of the Checks that Checkstyle provides by default
        use these methods to analyze the environment of the ASTs that
        are visited by the TreeWalker.  Don&#39;t abuse that feature for
        exploring the whole tree, though. Let the TreeWalker drive the
        tree traversal and limit the visitor to the neighbours of a
        single AST node.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Defining Check Properties">

      <p>
        OK Mr. Checkstyle, that&#39;s all very nice, but in my company we
        have several projects, and each has another number of allowed
        methods. I need to control my Check through properties, so where
        is the API to do that?
      </p>

      <p>
        Well, the short answer is, there is no API. It&#39;s magic. Really!
      </p>

      <p>
        If you need to make something configurable, just add a setter method
        to the Check:
      </p>

      <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
public class MethodLimitCheck extends AbstractCheck
{
  // code from above omitted for brevity
  public void setMax(int limit)
  {
    max = limit;
  }
}
      </code></pre></div>

      <p>
        With this code added, you can set the property <code>max</code> for the
        MethodLimitCheck module in the configuration file. It doesn&#39;t get any
        simpler than that. The secret is that Checkstyle uses
        <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/reflect/member/fieldValues.html">
        JavaBean reflection</a> to set the JavaBean properties. This works for all
        primitive types (for example boolean, int, and long), Strings, and arrays of these types.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Logging violations">

      <p>
        Detecting violations is one thing. Presenting them to the user is
        another. To do that, the Check base class provides several log
        methods, the simplest of them being <code>Check.log(String)</code>. In your
        Check you can simply use a verbatim violation string as the argument, i.e.
        <code>log(&quot;Too many methods, only &quot; + mMax +
        &quot; are allowed&quot;);</code>. This will
        work, but it&#39;s not the best possible solution if your Check is
        intended for a wider audience.
      </p>

      <p>
        If you are not living in a country where people speak English,
        you may have noticed that Checkstyle writes internationalized
        violation messages. For example, if you live in Germany the violation,
        messages are German. The individual Checks don&#39;t have to do
        anything fancy to achieve this. It&#39;s actually quite easy and the
        Checkstyle framework does most of the work.
      </p>

      <p>
        To support internationalized violation messages, you need to create or reuse an existing
        messages.properties file alongside your Check class (
        <a href="https://github.com/checkstyle/checkstyle/blob/master/src/main/resources/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/checks/sizes/messages.properties">
          example</a>).
        The Java file and the properties files should be in the same
        directory. Add a symbolic violation code and an English
        representation to the messages.properties. The file should
        contain the following line: <code>too.many.methods=Too many methods, only {0} are
        allowed</code>. Then replace the verbatim violation message with
        the symbolic representation and use one of the log helper
        methods to provide the dynamic part of the message (mMax in this
        case): <code>log(&quot;too.many.methods&quot;,
        mMax);</code>. Please consult the documentation of Java&#39;s
        <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/text/MessageFormat.html">
          MessageFormat</a>
        to learn about the syntax of format strings (especially about
        those funny numbers in the translated text).
      </p>

      <p>
        Supporting a new language is very easy now. Simply create a new
        messages file for the language, e.g. messages_fr.properties to
        provide French violation messages. The correct file will be chosen
        automatically, based on the language settings of the user&#39;s
        operating system.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Integrating Checks">

      <p>
        The great final moment has arrived! You are about to run your
        Check. To integrate your Check, add a new subentry under the
        TreeWalker module of your configuration file. Use the full
        classname of your Check class as the name of the module.
        Your configuration file <code>config.xml</code> should look something like this:
      </p>

      <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-xml">
&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot;?&gt;
&lt;!DOCTYPE module PUBLIC
    &quot;-//Checkstyle//DTD Checkstyle Configuration 1.3//EN&quot;
    &quot;https://checkstyle.org/dtds/configuration_1_3.dtd&quot;&gt;
&lt;module name=&quot;Checker&quot;&gt;
  &lt;module name=&quot;TreeWalker&quot;&gt;
          &lt;!-- your standard Checks that come with Checkstyle --&gt;
    &lt;module name=&quot;UpperEll&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;module name=&quot;MethodLength&quot;/&gt;
          &lt;!-- your Check goes here --&gt;
    &lt;module name=&quot;com.mycompany.checks.MethodLimitCheck&quot;&gt;
      &lt;property name=&quot;max&quot; value=&quot;45&quot;/&gt;
    &lt;/module&gt;
  &lt;/module&gt;
&lt;/module&gt;
      </code></pre></div>

      <p>
        To run the new Check on the command line compile your Check,
        create a jar that contains the classes and property files,
        e.g. <code>mycompanychecks.jar</code>. Then run
        (with the path separator
        <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/essential/environment/sysprop.html">
        system property ("path.separator")</a> adjusted to your platform:
        Linux/Unix - ":", Windows - ";"):
      </p>

      <p>For Linux/Unix OS:</p>
      <div class="wrap-content">
        <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
          java -classpath mycompanychecks.jar:checkstyle-${projectVersion}-all.jar \
          &#xa0;&#xa0;&#xa0;&#xa0;com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.Main -c config.xml myproject
        </code></pre></div>
      </div>

      <p>For Windows OS:</p>
      <div class="wrap-content">
        <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
          java -classpath mycompanychecks.jar;checkstyle-${projectVersion}-all.jar ^
          &#xa0;&#xa0;&#xa0;&#xa0;com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.Main -c config.xml myproject
        </code></pre></div>
      </div>

      <p>
        Did you see all those violations about &quot;too many methods&quot;
        flying over your screen? Congratulations. You can now consider
        yourself a Checkstyle expert. Go to your fridge. Have a beer.
      </p>

      <p>
        Please consult the <a href="config.html#Packages">Checkstyle
        configuration manual</a> to learn how to integrate your Checks
        into the package configuration so that you can use <code>MethodLimit</code> instead of the
        full class name.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Limitations">
      <p>
        There are only a few, but important, limitations for Checkstyle. These pertain to Java
        specifically, as well as regular text files.
      </p>
      <p>
        For Java,
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Code has to be compilable by <code>javac</code> to get valid violations.
          If it is not, you can get hard to understand parse errors.
        </li>
        <li>
          Java
          <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/specs/jls/se8/html/jls-3.html#jls-3.5">
            tokens (identifiers, keywords)</a>
          should be written with
          <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unicode">Unicode</a>
          characters ONLY,
          no
          <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/specs/jls/se8/html/jls-3.html#jls-3.3">
            Unicode escape sequence </a>
          support (i.e. <code>\uXXXX</code>) in keywords and identifiers.
        </li>
        <li>Javadoc comments are limited to
          <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASCII">ASCII</a> characters until
          <a href="https://github.com/checkstyle/checkstyle/issues/10629">
          Issue #10629.</a>
        </li>
        <li>You cannot determine the type of an expression.
        Example: "getValue() + getValue2()"</li>
        <li>You cannot determine the full inheritance hierarchy of type.</li>
        <li>We do not support any libraries that generates code in compile time using
          annotations like <code>@Getter</code> or <code>@Data</code>. see
          <a href="https://github.com/checkstyle/checkstyle/issues/13538#issuecomment-2799910922">issue #13538</a>
          for more details on workarounds.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        In addition to Java files, there are similar limitations that apply to all
        type of text files:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Checkstyle cannot properly handle a file's binary
          <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Byte_order_mark">
          Byte Order Mark (BOM)</a>, like UTF8's Unicode \uFEFF.
        </li>
        <li>
          You cannot see the contents of other files. You have access to the
          content of one file only during all Checks execution. All files
          are processed one by one.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        This means that you cannot implement some code inspection
        features that are available in advanced IDEs like Eclipse,
        <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/">IntelliJ IDEA</a>,
        <a href="https://spotbugs.github.io/">SpotBugs</a>,
        <a href="https://www.sonarsource.com/products/sonarqube/">Sonarqube</a>.
      </p>

      <p>
        For example you will not be able to implement:
        <br/>
        - a Check that finds redundant type casts or unused public methods.
        <br/>
        - a Check that validate that user custom Exception class inherited from
          java.lang.Exception class.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section name="Writing FileSetChecks">

      <p>Writing a FileSetCheck is usually required when you do not need to parse Java files
      to access the inner structure, or you are going to validate non "*.java" files.
      </p>

      <p>
        Writing a FileSetCheck is pretty straightforward! Just inherit from
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractFileSetCheck.html">
        AbstractFileSetCheck</a> and override the abstract
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/AbstractFileSetCheck.html#processFiltered-java.io.File-com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.FileText-">
          <code>processFiltered(java.io.File, java.util.List)</code>
        </a> method and you&#39;re done. A very simple example could fire a violation if the number
        of files exceeds a certain limit. Here is a FileSetCheck that does just that:
      </p>

      <div class="wrapper"><pre class="prettyprint"><code class="language-java">
package com.mycompany.checks;
import java.io.File;
import java.util.List;
import com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.api.*;

public class LimitImplementationFiles extends AbstractFileSetCheck
{
  private static final int DEFAULT_MAX = 100;
  private int fileCount;
  private int max = DEFAULT_MAX;
  public void setMax(int aMax)
  {
    this.max = aMax;
  }

  @Override
  public void beginProcessing(String aCharset)
  {
    super.beginProcessing(aCharset);

    //reset the file count
    this.fileCount = 0;
  }

  @Override
  public void processFiltered(File file, List&lt;String&gt; aLines)
  {
    this.fileCount++;

    if (this.fileCount > this.max) {
      // log the message
      log(1, "max.files.exceeded", Integer.valueOf(this.max));
      // you can call log() multiple times to flag multiple
      // violations in the same file
    }
  }
}
      </code></pre></div>

      <p>
        Note that the configuration via bean introspection also applies
        here. By implementing the <code>setMax()</code>
        method the FileSetCheck automatically makes &quot;max&quot; a
        legal configuration parameter that you can use in the Checkstyle
        configuration file.
      </p>
      <p>
        There are virtually no limits to what you can do in
        FileSetChecks, but please do not be crazy.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Declare check's external resource locations">
      <p>
        Checkstyle can cache external configuration resources of any kind which are used by your
        Check. If you want to do such a thing, you should implement the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/ExternalResourceHolder.html">
            ExternalResourceHolder</a>
        interface. Such a module must declare the external resource locations as a set of Strings
        which will be returned from the
        <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/ExternalResourceHolder.html#getExternalResourceLocations--">
          getExternalResourceLocations</a>
        method. This will allow Checkstyle to invalidate and clear the cache when the contents of at
        least one external configuration resource of your Check is changed.
      </p>
      <p>
        ATTENTION!
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          If
          <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/ExternalResourceHolder.html#getExternalResourceLocations--">
            getExternalResourceLocations</a>
          returns null, there will be a NullPointerException in
          <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/Checker.html">
            Checker</a>.
          Such behaviour signals that your module (check or filter) is designed incorrectly.
        </li>
        <li>
          It makes sense to return an empty set from
          <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/api/ExternalResourceHolder.html#getExternalResourceLocations--">
            getExternalResourceLocations</a>
          only for composite modules like
          <a href="apidocs/com/puppycrawl/tools/checkstyle/TreeWalker.html">
            TreeWalker</a>.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section name="Huh? I can&#39;t figure it out!">
      <p>
        That&#39;s probably our fault, and it means that we have to provide
        better documentation. Please do not hesitate to ask questions on
        the user <a href="mailing-lists.html">
        mailing lists</a>. This will help us to improve this
        document. Please ask your questions as precisely as possible.
        We will not be able to answer questions like &quot;I want to
        write a Check but I don&#39;t know how, can you help me?&quot;. Tell
        us what you are trying to do (the purpose of the Check), what
        you have understood so far, and what exactly you are getting stuck
        on.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="Contributing">
      <p>
        We need <em>your</em> help to keep improving Checkstyle.

        Whenever you write a Check or FileSetCheck that you think is
        generally useful, please consider
        <a href="contributing.html">contributing</a> it to the
        Checkstyle community and submit it for inclusion in the next
        release of Checkstyle.
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
