<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.imports.UnusedImportsCheck"
             name="UnusedImports"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.TreeWalker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Checks for unused import statements. An import statement
 is considered unused if:
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 It is not referenced in the file. The algorithm does not support wild-card
 imports like {@code import java.io.*;}. Most IDE's provide very sophisticated
 checks for imports that handle wild-card imports.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 The class imported is from the {@code java.lang} package. For example
 importing {@code java.lang.String}.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 The class imported is from the same package.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 A static method is imported when used as method reference. In that case,
 only the type needs to be imported and that's enough to resolve the method.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;Optionally:&lt;/b&gt; it is referenced in Javadoc comments. This check is on by
 default, but it is considered bad practice to introduce a compile-time
 dependency for documentation purposes only. As an example, the import
 {@code java.util.List} would be considered referenced with the Javadoc
 comment {@code {@link List}}. The alternative to avoid introducing a compile-time
 dependency would be to write the Javadoc comment as {@code {&amp;#64;link java.util.List}}.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 The main limitation of this check is handling the cases where:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 An imported type has the same name as a declaration, such as a member variable.
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;
 There are two or more static imports with the same method name
 (javac can distinguish imports with same name but different parameters, but checkstyle can not
 due to &lt;a href="https://checkstyle.org/writingchecks.html#Limitations"&gt;limitation.&lt;/a&gt;)
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <properties>
        <property default-value="true" name="processJavadoc" type="boolean">
          <description>Control whether to process Javadoc comments.</description>
        </property>
      </properties>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="import.unused"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
