<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<checkstyle-metadata>
  <module>
    <check fully-qualified-name="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.checks.coding.CovariantEqualsCheck"
             name="CovariantEquals"
             parent="com.puppycrawl.tools.checkstyle.TreeWalker">
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
 Checks that classes and records which define a covariant {@code equals()} method
 also override method {@code equals(Object)}.
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Covariant {@code equals()} - method that is similar to {@code equals(Object)},
 but with a covariant parameter type (any subtype of Object).
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt;: the enums are also checked,
 even though they cannot override {@code equals(Object)}.
 The reason is to point out that implementing {@code equals()} in enums
 is considered an awful practice: it may cause having two different enum values
 that are equal using covariant enum method, and not equal when compared normally.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.cs.jhu.edu/~daveho/pubs/oopsla2004.pdf"&gt;
 Finding Bugs is Easy, chapter '4.5 Bad Covariant Definition of Equals (Eq)'&lt;/a&gt;:
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Java classes and records may override the {@code equals(Object)} method to define
 a predicate for object equality. This method is used by many of the Java
 runtime library classes; for example, to implement generic containers.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 Programmers sometimes mistakenly use the type of their class {@code Foo}
 as the type of the parameter to {@code equals()}:
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;pre&gt;
 public boolean equals(Foo obj) {...}
 &lt;/pre&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 This covariant version of {@code equals()} does not override the version in
 the {@code Object} class, and it may lead to unexpected behavior at runtime,
 especially if the class is used with one of the standard collection classes
 which expect that the standard {@code equals(Object)} method is overridden.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;
 This kind of bug is not obvious because it looks correct, and in circumstances
 where the class is accessed through the references of the class type (rather
 than a supertype), it will work correctly. However, the first time it is used
 in a container, the behavior might be mysterious. For these reasons, this type
 of bug can elude testing and code inspections.
 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <message-keys>
        <message-key key="covariant.equals"/>
      </message-keys>
    </check>
  </module>
</checkstyle-metadata>
